Hello friends, welcome to my and your
YouTube4 Shial's Protect Gain Plan.
Friends, this is a unit linked life insurance
plan. In this, you get 20 fund options and
you get portfolio strategy
options. So friends, this can be a
great plan for you.
I am going to tell you all the details
in this video. So do not skip the video at all. If you are visiting the
channel for the first time, then
subscribe to the channel. So friends, first of all, let
us talk about eligibility.
Here, friends, you get
two options for premium payment. The first is
limited pay. Limited pay means
paying for fewer years than your policy term. Regular pay
means paying for as long as your policy term is.
In the case of limited pay,
friends, you will get to see the premium payment term of 5 to 12
years and
in the case of regular pay, you will get to see it of 30 to 40 years.
Talking about the policy term,
whether it is limited pay or regular pay,
you will get to see at least 30 to 40 years.
Friends, the entry age and maximum  The
entry age has been kept at 18 years and 60 years. The
minimum maturity age is 48 years and the maximum
maturity age is 90 years. The minimum
annual premium you will have to pay is Rs 40,000
and the minimum sum assured you will get is Rs
4 lakh.
Talking about premium payment, you can pay yearly, half yearly
or monthly mode. If
you want to pay a top-up premium, you can
also pay a top-up premium of at least Rs 2,000.
Now friends, as I told you
that you will get 20 fund options,
this is the complete list in front of you. The
first one is Focus 50 Fund, the second one is India
Growth Fund, and Maximizer V Opportunity
Fund. Friends, this is the complete list.
As you move down from one to
19, in all the funds,
you will have to pay an FMC of Rs 1.35 per annum.
FMC means Fund Management
Charges. It will cost you Rs 1.35 per annum annually.
And friends, the 20th one in this  The option is Money
Market Fund. Here, you will have to pay 0.75%.
Friends, let us look at the portfolio
strategy options in detail.
First comes the Fixed Portfolio
Strategy. In this, friends, you have to do all the work yourself.
You have to choose the fund
yourself. You have to decide
how much proportion of your premium you want to invest in which fund.
So,
you have to do all these things. In this strategy,
friends, you also get the automatic transfer facility.
What will happen in the Auto Transfer Strategy is that, suppose you have to choose two funds,
whether you choose equity debt
or equity and balance fund.
In this, friends, you can choose that
your money should first go to the balance fund and
then be transferred to the equity fund. Here
also, you have to choose how much proportion you want to invest where.
Friends,
in this, friends, you get unlimited free switches.
You
can do unlimited free switching between your funds at any time if you want.
If you choose the Fixed Portfolio
Strategy, then along with this,
friends, you also get premium redirection. In the
Fixed Portfolio Strategy,
if you want, you can switch between any one fund and
another.  In this you can increase or decrease your premium. The
second is
Target Asset Allocation Strategy.
In this strategy, you have to choose any two funds
and pay your premium in them. The
third is
Trigger Portfolio Strategy.
In Trigger Portfolio Strategy,
friends, what happens is that you have to take an equity
fund which is a multi-cap growth fund
and a debt-oriented fund which
we call income fund. You have to take these two funds.
Your money is invested in these funds at 75% in the multi-cap growth fund and at 25% in the income fund which is a debt-
oriented fund. Now
friends, as the name of this policy
is Trigger Portfolio Strategy,
when does the trigger event occur in this? Suppose the
NAV of the multi-cap fund you have taken is higher at 10 or lower at 10 or higher at
10, then whatever
profit you make above will be transferred to the liquid fund.
If it is below 10, then the
money from the liquid fund will be transferred to the equity fund, be it
mid-cap, to keep it balanced.  Be it index fund,
multi-cap growth fund or opportunity fund, if you
go to see the returns of all of them, they come out to be
above 10%. If we talk about
income fund, then its ROR is also
7.7%. The fourth strategy that
comes in this is life cycle based
portfolio strategy. What happens in this is that
as your age
increases, the money you would have
invested in multi-cap growth fund
decreases and your money
in income fund increases. If you see a
person of 25 years, his money will
go into growth fund at 80, multi-cap which is equity
based and at 20, the money is going
into income fund which is a debt fund. As the age of
this person increases and that person becomes 66 plus, then the
money which will start going into multi-cap will be
at 35 and
his money in income fund will be at 65. This
means that as the age increases, your money
invested in equity based will decrease
and the investment in income fund will
increase, due to which your  The risk
factor should keep decreasing. If we
talk about the charges, then first of all come the
premium allocation charges. Friends, mostly
you get the charges back in double or triple amounts.
I will tell you about that later. First of all, the
charges come premium allocation
charges. In the first year, you will have to pay 12% of your premium, in the
second and third year 5% and
in the third year 4.25% of your premium. From the fourth
year onwards, these stop being levied on you. The
second charges are policy
discontinuous charges. If you take out your
policy, you will have to pay a maximum discount in the first 4 years.
If you take out your
policy from the fifth year onwards, you will
not have to pay a discount on your policy. Next
come the policy administration
charges. Friends, these
can cost you a maximum of ₹5000000. Currently,
if we talk about it, you are being charged 0.34 for the annual premium,
which is taken from you on a monthly
basis. And these charges,
friends, start being levied from your fourth policy year.
Next comes
mortality charges, these totally depend on
your age.  In the Gender Sum Assured Pay Discontinued
Fund, friends, 0.50 of the fund value is going to be charged.
Talking about death
benefits, friends, the top-up sum assured will be seen along with the sum assured.
Both of these will be added
and compared with your fund
value. If you have topped up the fund value,
it will also be
compared with whatever premium you have paid,
including top-up, out of
105 of those, whichever is higher,
friends, that will be given to your nominee as a death
benefit. Next,
if we talk about maturity benefit, friends,
you are going to get your fund value.
Whatever your fund value has become,
you will get it. Talking about partial withdrawal, it is
locked in for the first 5 years,
you cannot withdraw it after that, in
which your minimum withdrawal should be
equal to ₹2000000 premium.
Next, friends, in this you
also get the option of systematic withdrawal plan.
If you want, you can withdraw your 5 year policy.
After the completion of the year, you
can also apply for a systematic withdrawal plan. The payouts you get in this can be
monthly, quarterly, half-yearly,
yearly, as you wish.
After that, friends, you
also get the option to change your premium payment term here.
Now, I had told you
that you get back many of your charges, so first of all,
you get
back the premium allocation charges, friends.
You get double the amount, but you do
not get the money for it. They are
added to your fund in the form of units. So, whatever
premium allocation charges you may have incurred, they will be
doubled and added to your fund
in the form of units. Next
comes the return of mortality charges, friends.
Mortality charges are
also returned to you up
to 25 years. If your policy term is more than 25 years,
then you
get them back four times from the 26th year onwards
in the form of units in your fund value.
Next, friends, the good thing that comes in this is the
maturity booster.
Friends, you will get the maturity booster in the
last eight policy quarters of your policy term,
so this
maturity booster friends is going to be 20% of your average
fund value.
Now friends, if you want to surrender, then you
can definitely surrender the policy after the lock-in
period is over. There is a lock-in period of 5 years.
After the lock-in period is over, you can also surrender your policy.
Okay friends, so friends,
we have shared all the details of this plan with you. If you have
any doubt, please let us
know by commenting. If you like the video and find it informative,
then like the video, subscribe to the channel
and
share it with as many of your friends as possible. See you
in the new video, till then, bye, take care.